<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming Club IIT Kanpur</title>
    <description>The Programming Club, IIT Kanpur
</description>
    <link>https://pclub.in/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://pclub.in/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 15:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 15:03:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bug Bounty on Hello IITK Platform</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To help strengthen the security of the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://hello.iitk.ac.in&quot;&gt;Hello IITK&lt;/a&gt; platform, we are starting a bug bounty program. We realize that when building a large platform, a small oversight on the part of the developers can lead to serious security bugs. While the developers of Hello IITK have tried their best to make the platform as secure as possible, there may still be some unfixed vulnerabilites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you believe you have found a security vulnerability on Hello IITK, we encourage you to let us know right away. We will investigate all legitimate reports and will help to get the problem fixed ASAP. If you wish to participate, read this entire document very carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;submitting-a-report&quot;&gt;Submitting a report&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can submit your reports by filling &lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/rkiQjcq6hD5XUGR29&quot;&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rewards&quot;&gt;Rewards&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will classify your report as one of the following, and you’ll get the corresponding rewards:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not a security vulnerability&lt;/strong&gt;: No rewards.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extremely low-risk vulnerability&lt;/strong&gt;: Mention in our Hall of Fame.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mild Severity Vulnerability&lt;/strong&gt;: Mention in our Hall of Fame + Amazon Gift Coupons worth INR 400&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medium Severity Vulnerability&lt;/strong&gt;: Mention in our Hall of Fame + Amazon Gift Coupons worth INR 600&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Severity Vulnerability&lt;/strong&gt;: Mention in our Hall of Fame + Amazon Gift Coupons worth INR 800&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In addition to the above, you may get a certificate awarded by the Institute. The certification, and the contents of the certificate, will be at the discretion of Prof. T. V. Prabhakar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;responsible-disclosure-policy&quot;&gt;Responsible Disclosure Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For you to participate in the program, we require that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You do not modify or access data from any other user’s account, without the account owner’s explicit consent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You try your best to avoid privacy violations and disruptions to others (which may include things like unauthorized access to or destruction of data, and interruption or degradation of the services of the Hello IITK platform).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If, while investigating an issue, you inadvertently access any data that you are not supposed to, you must promptly notify us and then immediately delete the information from your system. You must also acknowledge the inadvertent access in any related bug bounty report you may subsequently submit. You may not share the inadvertently accessed information with anyone else.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You do not exploit a security issue you discover for any reason other than for testing purposes, and you do not conduct testing outside of your own account, or another account for which you have the explicit written consent of the account owner to test.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You give us reasonable time to investigate and mitigate an issue you report before publicly disclosing any information about the report or sharing such information with others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t do anything that can dirsupt the proceeding of any course. For testing vulnerabilities that may provide unauthorized access to another user’s account, we encourage you to form teams and test the vulnerabilities on your teammates’ accounts only. Also, don’t share the details of the vulnerability publicly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;important-note&quot;&gt;Important Note&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any queries or API requests made by you, while logged in, may be tracked. So if you violate any rule, you will be liable to punishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-bounty-program-processes&quot;&gt;Bug Bounty Program Processes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will recognize and reward security researchers who help us secure the Hello IITK platform by reporting any found vulnerabilities. Rewards for such reports are entirely at the discretion of the organisers (that include the Coordinators of the Programming Club and Prof. T. V. Prabhakar’s team of developers), based on risk, impact, and other factors. To be considered for a bounty, you must meet the following requirements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adhere to our Responsible Disclosure Policy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Report a security bug: that is, identify a vulnerability in the platform which creates a security or privacy risk. (Note that the organisers ultimately determine the risk of an issue, and that many software bugs are not security issues.) Report the vulnerability upon discovery or as soon as is feasible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Submit your report via the form link given in the “Submitting a report” section of this document (one submission per report) and respond to any follow-up requests from the organisers for updates or further information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use your own or your teammates’ accounts when investigating issues. Do not use or interact with the account belonging to another person without explicit consent of the account owner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contact the coordinators of the Programming Club for clarification on anything not covered in these terms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In turn, we will follow these guidelines when evaluating reports under our bug bounty program:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We investigate and respond to all valid reports.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We determine the rewards based on a variety of factors, including (but not limited to) impact, ease of exploitation, and quality of the report. Note that extremely low-risk issues may not qualify for a bounty at all.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the event of duplicate reports, we award a bounty to the first person to submit an issue.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We reserve the right to publish reports (and accompanying updates).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We publish a list of researchers who have submitted valid security reports.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We may retain any communications about security issues you report for as long as we deem necessary for program purposes, and we may cancel or modify this program at any time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;issues-not-eligible-for-bounties&quot;&gt;Issues not eligible for bounties&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;out-of-scope&quot;&gt;Out of Scope&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spamming the platform.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social Engineering attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Denial-of-service attacks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that you may be subject to punishment if you perform any of the above mentioned attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;false-positives&quot;&gt;False positives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bugs that are not security vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reports that are not reproducible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accessing data that is available publicly by design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope that you will enjoy trying to find security bugs on the Hello IITK platform. Even if you don’t find any vulnerabilities, we hope it will be a great learning experience for you.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://pclub.in/events/2020/09/02/bug-bounty-on-hello-iitk.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pclub.in/events/2020/09/02/bug-bounty-on-hello-iitk.html</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>bugbounty</category>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Celebrating Open Source at IITK!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Statistics for Google Summer of Code 2020 are out, and we have a reason to celebrate. IIT Kanpur ranked 2nd worldwide in the list of universities with the most accepted students. The list is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://opensource.googleblog.com/2020/08/google-summer-of-code-2020-statistics.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our numbers have been increasing steadily over the last few years, as you can see in the table below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Number of accepted students&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;19&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;27&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, some of the previously selected students have also started becoming GSoC mentors for their organisations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following is the list of students selected in the year 2020:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Roll Number&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Organisation&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Aakash Lahoti&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;160004&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Linux Foundation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ahsan Barkati&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;160055&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;FreeBSD Project&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ankit Kumar&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;170124&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Blender Foundation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Apurva Nandan&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;170141&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The NetBSD Foundation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dipanshu Garg&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;190306&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Xapian Search Engine Library&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Karan Takalkar&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;180341&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Mifos Initiative&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kartikeya Sanwal&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;180348&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Terasology Foundation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Lakshay Bandlish&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;160360&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Linux Foundation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mohit Mohan&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;180429&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Linux Foundation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mohit Tyagi&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;160414&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;CERN-HSF&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Naman Jain&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;160427&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The NetBSD Foundation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Nidhi Hegde&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;180472&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;CERN-HSF&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Nilay Majorwar&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;180483&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;GDevelop&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Nirmal Praveen Suthar&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;180484&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Julia Language&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Preeti Menghwani&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;180550&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;apertus° Association&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Priydarshi Singh&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;180561&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Linux Foundation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Shivank Garg&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;160658&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;FreeBSD Project&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Shubh Gupta&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;160668&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;FreeBSD Project&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Suraj Verma&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;160726&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MZmine&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Utkarsh Rajput&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;170767&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Julia Language&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Vikrant Malik&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;180862&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;The Linux Foundation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my first year, I was once talking to yashsriv, a former coordinator of PClub. He recalled that during his time, IITK did not even feature in the list, while our sister IITs like KGP and Roorkee had 30+ selections. We have come a long way since then. Initiatives, that were started by the former coordinators years ago, and were continued in the subsequent years, have helped create a wonderful open source culture at IITK. In fact, besides GSoC, IITK students are starting to participate in other open source programmes (like Outreachy, Linux Foundation Mentorship Programme etc.) as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our tenure, we would certainly try to conduct more events that help people get started with open source development. In particular, we would try to help more first year students (if we have any) get selected. This time, we had only one Y19 UG selected for GSoC. It would be great to see many first year students in that list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to all those who have been successful in their open source journey! All the best to those who’ll try in the future! Keep hacking!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 14:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://pclub.in/events/2020/08/30/celebrating-open-source.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pclub.in/events/2020/08/30/celebrating-open-source.html</guid>
        
        <category>opensource</category>
        
        <category>gsoc</category>
        
        
        <category>events</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Travis CI</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The aim is to streamline all further development of LifeIITK such that there is consistency and reproducibility across developers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setup proper development, test and production environments for lifeiitk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;relevant-technologies&quot;&gt;Relevant Technologies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Docker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travis CI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;application-task&quot;&gt;Application Task&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;docker-compose.yml&lt;/code&gt; that spins up 3 docker containers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;node.js backend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;react frontend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;mysql database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reference look up &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yugeshk/hotel-management/blob/master/docker-compose.yml&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;repository&quot;&gt;Repository&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/life-iitk&quot;&gt;Life@IITK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mentor&quot;&gt;Mentor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yugesh Kothari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-travis-ci.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-travis-ci.html</guid>
        
        <category>winter19</category>
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        <category>Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nomination Portal</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The portal will be used to announce empty positions in gymkhana and students can apply for the positions on portal itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will have the following projects :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating new positions and announcing vacancy: It will be used by authorised users to create new positions in gymkhana whenever required and to announce vacancies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Filing nominations: Students can apply for vacant positions using the portal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This portal will be added to the Life@IITK application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;relevant-technologies&quot;&gt;Relevant Technologies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;repository&quot;&gt;Repository&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/life-iitk&quot;&gt;Life@IITK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mentor&quot;&gt;Mentor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aditya Gulati&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-nomination-portal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-nomination-portal.html</guid>
        
        <category>winter19</category>
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        <category>Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Music App</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Develop a music app for the campus with the following features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;See music that friends are playing currently&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Private mode to hide currently playing music&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Music rooms - to livestream music to all users currently using the app and live updation of playlists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project will have multiple members. (approximately 3 to 4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;application-task&quot;&gt;Application Task&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setup the below mentioned repo and get it run locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;relevant-technologies&quot;&gt;Relevant Technologies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TypeScript/JavaScript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;repository&quot;&gt;Repository&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Cloud-Player/web&quot;&gt;Music Player&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mentor&quot;&gt;Mentor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yugesh Kothari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-music.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-music.html</guid>
        
        <category>winter19</category>
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        <category>Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mess Portal</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;lifeiitk&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/life-iitk&quot;&gt;Life@IITK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mess-portal&quot;&gt;Mess portal&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mess portal will be used as a one stop to view mess menu and other details such as timing of all messes. It will be a feature integrated in Life IITK app.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-mess-portal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-mess-portal.html</guid>
        
        <category>winter19</category>
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        <category>Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Map Integration</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop a 3D map for the Life IITK app.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The map will have all the locations of campus tagged and can be used to see the upcoming events at any venue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;relevant-technologies&quot;&gt;Relevant Technologies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Django&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;React&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;repository&quot;&gt;Repository&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/life-iitk&quot;&gt;Life@IITK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mentor&quot;&gt;Mentor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aditya Gulati&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-map.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-map.html</guid>
        
        <category>winter19</category>
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        <category>Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Election Portal</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;lifeiitk&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/life-iitk&quot;&gt;Life@IITK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;election-portal&quot;&gt;Election portal&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Portal that will handle all the election related work online will be developed and integrated to the currently existing Life IITK app. It will include the following projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Position creation: To create and notify about new positions for elections only by authorised accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Filing nominations: To file nominations for running in elections. This will also submitting details of campaigners.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Actual voting: To handle voting on election day. It should be secure and able to cater to the election day needs of institute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;repository&quot;&gt;Repository&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/life-iitk&quot;&gt;Life@IITK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mentor&quot;&gt;Mentor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Priydarshi Singh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-election-portal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-election-portal.html</guid>
        
        <category>winter19</category>
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        <category>Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Buy and Sell</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The current buy and sell forum of iitk on facebook is very disorganised and chaotic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop and integrate a portal to buy and sell things on campus into the Life@IITK app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;relevant-technologies&quot;&gt;Relevant Technologies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Django&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;React&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;repository&quot;&gt;Repository&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/life-iitk&quot;&gt;Life@IITK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mentor&quot;&gt;Mentor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aditya Gulati&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-buy-and-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-buy-and-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>winter19</category>
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        <category>Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blogs</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;description&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop a blog feature for the Life@IITK app, where various clubs and cells can put up their blogs and students can follow blogs of their interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;relevant-technologies&quot;&gt;Relevant Technologies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Django&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;React&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;repository&quot;&gt;Repository&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/life-iitk&quot;&gt;Life@IITK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mentor&quot;&gt;Mentor&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aditya Gulati&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-blogs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://pclub.in/wocproject/project/2019/10/25/lifeiitk-blogs.html</guid>
        
        <category>winter19</category>
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        
        <category>wocproject</category>
        
        <category>Project</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
